

# **Europass** curriculum vitae

### Personal information

Surname(s) / First name(s)

Address(es)

Telephone(s)

Fax(es)

E-mail(s)

Nationality(-ies)

Date of birth

Gender

Male

Slovak

1.6.1977

Hric / Peter

+421 - 950 - 499 - 887

hric.peter@gmail.com

# Desired employment / Occupational field

# Senior IT developer (respectively team leader)

Stará Cesta 244/78, Teplička nad Váhom – county of Žilina, Slovakia

I agree to assess my seniority level based on my previous experience in particular field and Your company's standards.

# Work experience

Dates

May 2016 - December 2016

Occupation or position held Main activities and responsibilities

Mobile application developer - Freelancer

Multi-platfrom mobile solution selection, design and creation of a client-server mobile application and PHP/ MySQL server side.

IT Technologies: NetBeans, CodeNameOne, Android Studio, Eclipse, Java, MySQL, WorkBench, GIT, PHP, JSON

Name and address of employer Type of business or sector

SmartBooks, a.s. Národná 18, 01001 Žilina http://www.smartbooks.sk

Smart education, Education Management System

Dates

July 2014 - July 2016

Occupation or position held Main activities and responsibilities Analyst / designer / programmer / project coordinator Analyze, design, implement and document software based on "technical requirements given by goal

definition" alone or with team of co-developers.

- Development of real-time COM/CAN interface drivers under IntervalZero's RTX

- Creation of smart algorithm autonomous decision system, dispatching robots according to incoming messages from PLC and based on current manufacture hall status, Hall statistics backend, License server for CEIT Software components.

IT Technologies: C# .NET 3.5/4.5 C/C++, VS2008-2015, Eclipse, MySQL Workbench, Redmine, JIRA, Interval Zero RTX, WinXP embedded, Win Server 2008

Name and address of employer Type of business or sector **CEIT Technical Innovation**, Univerzitná 8661/6A Žilina, Slovakia http://www.ceitgroup.eu/

Manufacture process automation, mechatronics

Dates

Oct 2013 - June 2014

Occupation or position held

Define, design, develop, testing and documentation of mobile platform applications.

Page 1 - Curriculum vitae of

For more information go to http://europass.cedefop.eu.int

Surname(s) First name(s)

Main activities and responsibilities

All activities that belong to mobile app development and its life-cycle.

IT Technologies: C# with Xamarin and JAVA with Eclipse ADT, partly IntelliJ IDEA, SVN, Git, Android

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

**Self employment**, volunteer, self-skill building Information Technology, Mobile platform apps

Dates

May 2005 - Sept 2013

Occupation or position held Main activities and responsibilities

IT developer, Team leader

1<sup>st</sup> Project: WiMAX / LTE – General Agile development method (duration 7+ years):

Design, implementation, testing and reporting of System and Link Level wireless network simulator and tools. R&D in wireless technologies: OFDM, IFDMA, WiMAX, LTE

IT Technologies: Matlab, Scilab, C++ under UNIX, Clearcase, SVN, UML design with Rational Rose, XML

#### 2<sup>nd</sup> Project: TETRA – SCRUM development method (duration: 15 months):

Multi network dispatching and surveillance system (Tetra, ISDN, PSTN, GSM-R). Implementation of new features, testing, version control within existing architecture and international team of developers.

IT Technologies: OO Design Patterns, Multi-thread server-client application programming, MS Visual Studio 2008, Eclipse Java/C++, ACE library, ASN structured language, SQLite, PostgreSQL, SVN, Mantis BT, Hudson, Jenkins CI, Target platforms: Linux/Windows

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

Siemens PSE s.r.o, Dúbravská cesta 4, Bratislava – Slovakia

Information Technology, SW development, Telecommunications

Dates

Jan 2003 - May 2005

IT developer

Occupation or position held Main activities and responsibilities

Design, implementation, and reporting – Development of embedded SW for end user telecom terminals, Multi Function Fax/Copier/Scanner

IT Technologies: C/C++ under Nucleus OS, MKS source control, Lotus Notes bug tracking & mailing

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

Sagem Communications SA, Gutheil-Schödergasse 5, Vienna – Austria

Information Technology, DSP, embedded SW/HW development, Telecommunications

Dates

May 2002 - Dec 2002

Occupation or position held Main activities and responsibilities

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

#### Junior IT developer

SW Development – drivers and applications for Widows CE for company product Hand Held PC:

Gotive H42 WEC (Wireless Enterprise Communicator)

IT Technologies: Microsoft Embedded C, MFC, C++, MS Source Safe

Gotive s.r.o, Zámocká 34, Bratislava – Slovakia

Information Technology, SW/HW development, Computer Science, Embedded R&D

Dates

Sept 2001 - Apr 2002

Occupation or position held

Junior IT developer – IAESTE Trainee

Main activities and responsibilities

Matlab simulations, DSP code implementation and optimization, SW development

IT Technologies: Matlab, DSP Assembler, C/C++, Texas Instruments Code Composer Studio, Microsoft Visual C 6.0, Microsoft COM (Component Object Model)

Name and address of employer

Oticon S/A, Kongebakken 9, 2765 Smørum, Denmark

Page 2 - Curriculum vitae of Surname(s) First name(s)

For more information go to http://europass.cedefop.eu.int

Type of business or sector

R&D in audio coding and wireless transmission, Information Technology, SW/HW development, Computer Science

**Dates** 

Jan 2001 – June 2001 (During undergraduate university studies)

Occupation or position held

Martin a satisfat a consultant and a second state of

Programming and testing of GUI component classes

Junior/Student IT developer - ALES a.s.

Main activities and responsibilities

IT Technologies: NeXT STEP (Unix Like) <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NeXTSTEP">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NeXTSTEP</a>, Objective C

Name and address of employer

ALES a.s. Soblahovska 2050 Trencin, Slovakia http://www.ales.sk

Type of business or sector

Aviation Navigation Systems for airport dispatchers, Information Technology, SW/HW development

## **Training**

**Dates** 

Sept 2011

Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered

Linux scripting: Ruby / RubyMine

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

MINIO s.r.o. Bratislava - Slovakia

Dates

July 2011

Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered

Scripting and programming in UNIX shell

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

CIS - Computer Information Systems s.r.o. Bratislava - Slovakia

Dates

June 2009

Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered

UML notation and documentation

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

Gopas a.s. Bratislava – Slovakia

Dates

es | June 2008

Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered

Advanced techniques in C++ programming

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

Gopas a.s. Bratislava - Slovakia

Dates

May 2006

Principal subjects/Occupational skills

C++ programming under Linux part I and part II

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

CIS - Computer Information Systems s.r.o. Bratislava - Slovakia

Dates

Mar 2006

Principal subjects/Occupational skills

Scripting and programming under Unix

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

Siemens PSE s.r.o. Bratislava - Slovakia

Dates

Sept 2004

Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered

**UML** - basic training

Page 3 - Curriculum vitae of

For more information go to http://europass.cedefop.eu.int

Surname(s) First name(s)

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

CIS - Computer Information Systems s.r.o. Bratislava - Slovakia

# **Education**

**Dates** 

Sept 1995 - Jun 2001

Title of qualification awarded Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered

MScEE. Master of Science - Electrical Engineering - with red diploma honors Telecommunications, Radio and electrical engineering, Multimedia, DSP, Programming

Secondary Technical school of Joseph Murgaš, Hurbanova 6, Banská Bystrica - Slovakia

Name and type of organisation providing education and training Technical University of Košice Letná 9, Košice – Slovakia Department of radio-electronics and multimedia telecommunications

Level in national or international classification Recognised nation and Europe wide

Dates

Sept 1991 - Jun 1995

Title of qualification awarded

High school graduation - with honors

Principal subjects/Occupational skills

Audio and Video techniques, electronics

Name and type of organisation providing education and training

Level in national or international classification

# Personal skills and competences

Mother tongue(s)

Slovak, Czech

Other language(s)
Self-assessment
European level (\*)

English German

Understanding		Speaking		Writing
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C1	C2	C1	C1	C1
B1	B1	A2	B1	B1

<sup>(\*)</sup> Common European Framework of Reference (CEF) level

Technical skills and competences

STL (Standard Template Library)	Advanced	90 %
Object oriented programming and documentation	Advanced	80 %
Design Patterns	Advanced	70 %
Multi-thread programming	Advanced	65 %
RealTime OS (Nucleus, WinCE)	Intermediate	60 %
Embedded HW systems understanding and analysis, Embedded SW development	Intermediate	50 %
Mobile applications (Native Android and multi-platform IDE)	Intermediate	40 %
Linux shell scripting	Intermediate	40 %
HW design, analysis	Beginner	35 %

Computer skills and competences

C++	Advanced	85 %
XML, HTML	Advanced	70 %
C, C#	Advanced	65 %
UML notation, RUP Design	Advanced	65 %
Unix / Linux / Shell	Intermediate	60 %
Databases (MySQL, SQLite , MS SQL)	Intermediate	55 %
.NET	Intermediate	55 %
Java (Android)	Intermediate	50 %
Matlab, Simulink, SciLab	Intermediate	50 %
Assembler (DSP, microcontroller)	Intermediate	45 %
Objective C	Intermediate – self study	40 %
PHP	Beginner	30 %
RUBY, VHDL, Verilog	Beginner – self study, Training	10 %

Organisational skills and competences

3 years of team leading. Job focused on development of a simulator tool for 4G wireless network deployment (LTE/WiMAX). Telecom algorithms evaluation and improvement.

Apart from leading the technical part of this position, I was responsible for motivation of team members and assessment of their effort, which also included personal rewarding proposals.

Social skills and competences

As a team leader and motivator, or as a team member I worked in multinational environments in three different companies.

While working at Siemens, I had to daily cooperate with colleagues in Germany, Austria, Denmark, Hungary, Croatia, China and Slovakia. In Sagem I also cooperated with French colleagues.

Other skills and competences

Team leading and motivation. Technical requirements analysis. (Both acquired during work.)

Page 5 - Curriculum vitae of Surname(s) First name(s)

For more information go to http://europass.cedefop.eu.int

Artistic skills and competences

Driving licence(s)

Additional information

Guitar and flute play, acting, dancing

Personal Car ~ 320.000 km

Creative work is a very strong motivation factor for my personality.

**Annexes**